can affect the output of when you prompt an LLM.
在提示LLM时的输出结果。
system as well as user messages and understand what you can do with that capability.
也可以指定用户消息的方法，了解
您可以利用这种功能做什么。
Let's take a look.
让我们来看看。
First, how does a large language model work?
首先，大型语言模型是如何工作的？
You're probably familiar with the text generation process where you can give a prompt, "I love
您可能已经熟悉了文本生成过程，您可
以给出一个提示，比如“我喜欢吃”，
And it may say "bagels with cream cheese" or "my mother's meatloaf" or "out with friends".
它可能会说“百吉饼加奶油奶酪”或“我妈
妈做的肉饼”或“和朋友一起在外面（吃）”。
But how did the model learn to do this?
但是模型是如何学会这个的呢？
The main tool used to train an LLM is actually supervised learning.
实际上，训练LLM的主要工具是监督学习。
In supervised learning, a computer learns an input/output or X/Y mapping using labeled
在监督学习中，计算机使用带标签的训
练数据学习输入/输出或X/Y映射。
training data.
So, for example, if you're using supervised learning to learn to classify the sentiment
所以，例如，如果你使用监督
学习来学习对餐厅评价
of restaurant reviews, you might collect a training set like this, where a review like
进行好评/差评分类，你可能会
收集这样的训练集，其中像
And "service was slow, the food was so-so" is negative and "the earl grey tea was fantastic"
而“服务慢，食物一般”是差
评，“伯爵灰茶非常棒”
has a positive label.
带有正面标签。
By the way, both Isa and I were born in the UK and so both of us like our earl grey tea.
顺便说一下，Isa和我都出生在英国，
所以我们都喜欢我们的伯爵茶。
And so the process for supervised learning is typically to get labeled data and then
因此，监督学习的过程通常是
获得带标签的数据，然后
train a model on data and after training, you can then deploy and call the model and
在数据上训练一个模型，训练完成
后，您可以部署并调用该模型，
give it a new restaurant review like "best pizza I've ever had".
给它一个新的餐厅评论，比如
"我吃过的最好的披萨"。
You hopefully output that that has a positive sentiment.
希望您能输出这是一个积极的情感。
It turns out that supervised learning is a core building block for training large language
事实证明，监督学习是训练大型
语言的核心构建模块模型。
models.
Specifically, a large language model can be built by using supervised learning to repeatedly
具体来说，可以通过使用监督学习来反复
predict the next word.
预测下一个单词来构建大型语言模型。
Let's say that in your training set of a lot of text data, you have to sentence "my favorite
假设在您的训练集中有很多文本数
据，您必须将句子"我最喜欢的
food is a bagel with cream cheese and mozz".
食物是百吉饼配上奶油奶酪和熏鲑鱼"。
Then this sentence is turned into a sequence of training examples where given a sentence
那么这个句子就会变成一个训
练示例序列，给定一个句子
fragment "my favorite food is a" if you want to predict the next word in this case was
片段"我最喜欢的食物是"，如果你想
预测下一个单词，这种情况下是
"bagel" or given the sentence fragment or sentence prefix "my favorite food is a bagel",
"百吉饼"，或者给定句子片段或句子
前缀"我最喜欢的食物是百吉饼"，
the next word in this case would be "with" and so on.
接下来的单词就是"配上"，依此类推。
And given a large training set of hundreds of billions or sometimes even more words,
而且，给定一个包含数千亿甚
至更多单词的大型训练集，
you can then create a massive training set where you can start off with part of a sentence
你就可以创建一个庞大的训练
集，从一句话的一部分开始
or part of a piece of text and repeatedly ask the language model to learn to predict
或者一段文字的一部分，反
复让语言模型学会预测
what is the next word.
下一个单词是什么。
So today there are broadly two major types of large language models.
所以今天有两种主要类
型的大型语言模型。
The first is a base LLM and the second which is what is increasingly used is the instruction
第一种是基础LLM，第二种是越来
越多地被使用的指令调优
LLM（Instruction Tuned LLM）。
Tuned LLM.
So the base LLM repeatedly predicts the next word based on text training data.
所以基础LLM会根据文本训练
数据反复预测下一个单词。
And so if I give it a prompt "once upon a time there was a unicorn" then it may by repeatedly
因此，如果我给它一个提示“从前有一个
独角兽”，那么它可能会通过反复地
predicting one word at a time come up with a completion that tells a story about a unicorn
一次预测一个单词，编写一
个关于独角兽的故事，
living in a magical forest with all unicorn friends.
讲述独角兽与所有独角兽朋友一
起生活在一个神奇的森林里。
Now a downside of this is that if you were to prompt it with "what is the capital of
现在的一个缺点是，如果你给它一
个提示“法国的首都是什么？”
France?"
quite plausible that on the internet there might be a list of quiz questions about France.
在互联网上很有可能存在关于
法国的一系列测验问题。
So it may complete this with "what is France's largest city?"
所以它可能会用“法国最大的城
市是什么？”来完成这个问题，
"what is France's population?" and so on.
“法国的人口是多少？”等等。
But what you really want is you want it to tell you what is the capital of France probably
但是你真正想要的是让它告
诉你法国的首都是什么，
rather than list all these questions.
而不是列出所有这些问题。
So the Instruction Tuned LLM instead tries to follow instructions and will hopefully
所以，指令调优LLM尝试遵循指
令，并希望能正确回答出，
say the capital of France is Paris.
法国的首都是巴黎。
How do you go from a base LLM to an Instruction Tuned LLM?
如何从基础LLM转变为指令调优LLM？
This is what the process of training an Instruction Tuned LLM like ChatGPT looks like.
这就是训练一个类似ChatGPT
的指令调优LLM的过程。
You first train a base LLM on a lot of data so hundreds of billions of words maybe even
首先，你需要在大量数据上训练一
个基础LLM，可能是数千亿甚至
it on a smaller set of examples where the output follows an input instruction.
来进一步训练它，这些例子
的输出遵循输入的指令。
And so for example you may have contractors help you write a lot of examples of an instruction
所以，例如，你可以请负责数据标注的承
包商帮助你编写很多指令的示例，
and then a good response to an instruction and that creates a training set to carry out
以及如何对这些指令高质量的回应，这
样就形成了一套训练集，可以进行
to follow an instruction.
ratings of the quality of many different LLM outputs on criteria such as whether the output
对许多不同LLM输出质量
的评分，例如输出是否
is helpful, honest, and harmless and you can then further tune the LLM to increase the
有帮助、诚实和无害，然后您可
以进一步调整LLM以提高
probability of its generating the more highly rated outputs.
生成更高评分输出的概率。
And whereas training the base LLM can take months the process of going from the base
而训练基础LLM可能需要几
个月的时间，从基础LLM
LLM to the instruction tune LLM can be done in maybe days on a much more modest size data
到指令调优LLM的过程可能只
需要几天时间，数据集规模
set and much more modest size computational resources.
和计算资源都要小得多。
So this is how you would use an LLM.
所以这就是你如何使用LLM的方法。
I'm going to import a few libraries.
我将导入一些库。
I'm going to load my OpenAI key here.
我将在这里加载我的OpenAI密钥。
I'll say a little bit more about this later in this video.
稍后在这个视频中，我会
更详细地介绍这个。
And here's a helper function to get a completion given a prompt.
这里有一个辅助函数，用于根据
提示获取补全（completion）。
If you have not yet installed the OpenAI package on your computer you might have to run pip
如果您还没有在计算机上安装
OpenAI软件包，您可能需要运行pip
install OpenAI but I already have it installed here so I won't run that.
安装OpenAI，但我已经在这里安
装了，所以我不会运行那个。
And let me hit shift enter to run these and now I can set response equals get completion
让我按shift enter运行这些，现在我可
以设置response=get_completion
"what is the capital of France?" and hopefully it will give me a good result.
“法国的首都是什么？”，希望
它能给我一个好结果。
Now about now in the description of the large language model so far I talked about it as
现在关于大型语言模型的描述
，到目前为止，我谈论的是
predicting one word at a time but there's actually one more important technical detail.
一次预测一个单词，但实际上还
有一个更重要的技术细节。
If you were to tell it "Take the letters in the word lollipop and reverse them".
如果你让它“把单词
lollipop中的字母倒过来”。
This seems like an easy task maybe like a four year old could do this task but if you
这看起来像是一个简单的任务，也许一个
四岁的孩子就能完成这个任务，但如果你
were to ask ChatGPT to do this it actually outputs a somewhat garbled whatever this is.
让ChatGPT去做这个，它实际上输出
的是一种有点乱七八糟的东西。
This is not L-O-L-L-I-P-O-P this is not lollipop's letters reversed.
这不是L-O-L-L-I-P-O-P，这不
是lollipop的字母倒过来。
So why is ChatGPT unable to do what seems like a relatively simple task.
那么为什么ChatGPT无法完成
看似相对简单的任务呢。
It turns out that there's one more important detail for how a large language model works
事实证明，大型语言模型的工作
方式还有一个更重要的细节，
which is it doesn't actually repeatedly predict the next word it instead repeatedly predicts
那就是它实际上不是反复预测
下一个单词，而是反复预测
the next token and what an LLM actually does is it will take a sequence of characters like
下一个标记（Token），而一个LLM实际上会
做的是，它会接收一系列字符，比如
"learning new things is fun" and group the characters together to form tokens that comprise commonly
“learning new things is fun”，并
将字符组合在一起形成代表常见
occurring sequences of characters.
字符序列的标记。
So here "learning new things is fun" each of them is a fairly common word and so each token
所以在这里“learning new things is
fun”，每个都是相当常见的词，所以每个标记
corresponds to one word or one word in a space or an exclamation mark.
对应一个词或一个词的空格或感叹号。
But if you were to give it input with some somewhat less frequently used words like "Prompting
但是，如果你给它一些不太常用的
词作为输入，比如“Prompting
is powerful developer tool." the word "Prompting" is still not that common in the English language
is a powerful developer tool.”
对于开发者来说，Prompting这个词
在英语中还不是那么常见
but certainly gaining in popularity and so "Prompting" is actually broken down to three
但肯定越来越受欢迎，所以
“Prompting”实际上被分解成三个
tokens with prompt, pt and ing because those three are commonly occurring sequences of
标记，分别是"prompt"、"pt"和"ing"
，因为这三个是常见的字母序列
letters and if you were to give it the word lollipop the tokenIsa actually breaks this
如果你给它一个“棒棒糖
（lollipop）”这个词，分词器实际上
把这个
down into three tokens "l" and "o" and "ipop" and because ChatGPT isn't seeing the individual
分成三个标记"l"、"o"和"ipop"，
因为ChatGPT没有看到单独的
letters is instead seeing these three tokens it's more difficult for it to correctly print
字母，而是看到了这三个标记，所
以要正确地按相反的顺序打印
out these letters in reverse order.
出这些字母就更困难了。
So here's a trick you can use to fix this if I were to add dashes between these letters
所以这里有一个技巧，如果我在
这些字母之间加上破折号，
and spaces would work too or other things would work too and take the letters and lollipop
空格也可以，或者其他东西也可以
，然后把字母和棒棒糖拿过来
and reverse them then it actually does a much better job this LOLLIPOP and the reason for
反过来，它实际上做得更好，
这个LOLLIPOP，原因是
that is if you pass it lollipop with dashes in between the letters it tokenizes each of
如果你用破折号把lollipop的
字母隔开，它会把每一个
these characters into an individual token making it easier for it to see the individual
这些字符分成一个个的标记，
让它更容易看到单独的
letters and print them out in reverse order.
字母，然后按相反的顺序打印出来。
So if you ever want to use ChatGPT to play a word game like wordle or scrap or something
所以如果你想用ChatGPT玩像
wordle或scrap这样的单词游戏，
this nifty trick helps it to better see the individual letters of the words.
这个巧妙的技巧有助于更好
地看到单词的各个字母。
For the English language one token roughly on average corresponds to about four characters
对于英语，一个标记大致
平均对应四个字符，
or about three quarters of a word and so different large language models will often have different
或者大约三分之二个单词，所以不同
的大型语言模型通常会有不同的
limits on the number of input plus output tokens it can accept.
关于它可以接受的输入加
输出标记的数量限制。
The input is often called the context and the output is often called the completion
输入通常被称为上下文（context），输
出通常被称为补全（completion）
and the model GPT 3.5 turbo for example the most commonly used ChatGPT model has a limit
例如，最常用的ChatGPT模型GPT-3.5
Turbo在输入和输出中的限制
of roughly 4000 tokens in the input plus output.
大约是4000个标记。
So if you try to feed it an input context that's much longer than this so actually throw
所以，如果你尝试输入一个超过这个
长度的上下文，它实际上会抛出
an exception or generate an error.
一个异常或产生一个错误。
Next I want to share with you another powerful way to use an LLM API which involves specifying
接下来，我想和你分享另一种使用
LLM API的强大方法，它涉及指定
separate system user and assistant messages.
独立的系统（system）、用户
（user）和助手（assistant）消息。
Let me show you an example then we can explain in more detail what it's actually doing.
让我给你展示一个例子，然后我们可以
更详细地解释它实际上在做什么。
Here's a new helper function called get completion from messages and when we prompt this LLM
这里有一个新的辅助函数，叫做从消息
中获取补全，当我们提示这个LLM时
we are going to give it multiple messages.
我们将给它提供多条消息。
Here's an example of what you can do.
这是一个你可以做的例子。
I'm going to specify first a message in the role of a system so this assistant message
首先，我将以系统的角色指定一
条信息，以便这个助手信息
and the content of the system message is you're an assistant who responds in the style of
系统信息的内容是，你是一个以
苏斯博士的风格回应的助手。
Dr. Seuss.
Then I'm going to specify a user message so the role of the second message is role
然后我将指定一个用户信息，所
以第二条信息的角色是用户，
user and the content of this is write me a very short poem about a happy carrot.
而这个内容是“给我写一首关于
快乐胡萝卜的非常短的诗。”
And so let's run that and with temperature equals one I actually never know what's going
所以让我们运行这个，温度
（Temperature）参数设置为1，我
实际上永远不知道会出现什么
to come out but okay that's a cool poem.
但好吧，这是一首很酷的诗。
"Oh how jolly is this carrot that I see" and it actually runs pretty well.
“哦，我看到的这根胡萝卜是多么快乐
”，而且它实际上运行得相当好。
All right well done ChatGPT.
好吧，干得好ChatGPT。
And so in this example the system message specifies the overall tone of what you want
所以在这个例子中，系统
消息指定了你想要的
the large language model to do and the user message is a specific instruction that you
大语言模型的整体语言风格，而
用户消息是一个具体的指令，
wanted to carry out given this higher level behavior that was specified in the system
你希望在系统中执行这个
更高级别的行为消息。
message.
Here's an illustration of how it all works.
这里有一个说明它是如何工作的例子。
So this is how the chat format works.
所以这就是聊天格式的工作原理。
The system message sets the overall tone of behavior of the large language model or the
系统消息设定了大型语言模型或
assistant and then when you give the user message such as maybe such as a tell me a
助手的整体行为风格，然后当你
给出用户消息，比如说“给我
joke or write me a poem it will then output an appropriate response following what you
讲个笑话或者写首诗”，它会根据
你在用户消息中要求的内容，
asked for in the user message and consistent with the overall behavior set in the system
以及在系统消息中设定的整体行
为风格，输出一个合适的回应。
message.
And by the way although I'm not illustrating it here if you want to use this in a multi-term
顺便说一下，虽然我没有在这里展
示，但如果你想在多轮对话中
conversation you can also input assistant messages in this messages format to let ChatGPT
使用这个功能，你也可以用这种消息
格式输入助手消息，让ChatGPT
know what it had previously said if you wanted to continue the conversation based on things
了解它之前说过什么，如果你想根
据之前的对话继续对话的话。
that had previously said as well.
But here are a few more examples.
但是这里有更多的例子。
If you want to set the tone to tell it to have a one sentence long output then in the
如果你想设置语言风格，告
诉它输出一句话，那么在
system message I can say all your responses must be one sentence long and when I execute
系统消息中，我可以说你的所有回
答都必须是一句话长，当我执行
this it outputs a single sentence is no longer a poem not in the style of Dr. Seuss but this
这个操作时，它输出的一句话不再是诗
歌，也不是苏斯博士的风格，但这
is a single sentence that's a story about the happy carrot.
是一句关于快乐胡萝卜的故事。
message to say in the system response to style Dr. Seuss all your sentences must be one sentence
在系统回应中说，以苏斯博士的风格，
你的所有句子都必须是一句话长，
I like that that's a very happy poem.
我喜欢这是一首非常快乐的诗。
And then lastly just for fun if you are using an LLM and you want to know how many tokens
然后最后，只是为了好玩，如果你在
使用LLM，想知道有多少个tokens
are you using here's a helper function that is a little bit more sophisticated in that
你在这里使用了一个稍微
复杂一点的辅助函数。
to tell you how many prompt tokens completion tokens and total tokens were used in your
告诉你在你的API调用中使用了多
少“prompt tokens”、“completion
tokens”和“total tokens”。
API call.
tokens we use.
tokens的计数。
So this output which had 55 tokens whereas the prompt input had 37 tokens so this used
所以这个输出有55个tokens，而提
示输入有37个tokens，所以这个
up 92 tokens altogether.
一共使用了92个tokens。
When I'm using LLM models in practice I don't worry that much frankly about the number of
当我在实践中使用LLM模型时，我实际上
并不太担心我使用的tokens数量。
tokens I'm using.
Maybe one case where it might be worth checking the number of tokens is if you're worried
也许在一个情况下，检查tokens数
量是值得的，那就是如果你担心
that the user might have given you too long an input that exceeds the 4000 or so token
用户可能给你太长的输入，超
过了4000个左右的tokens
limits of ChatGPT in which case you could double check how many tokens it was and truncate
ChatGPT的限制，在这种情况下，你可以
仔细检查一下tokens数量并截断
it to make sure you're staying within the input token limits of the large language model.
它以确保你在大型语言模型的
输入tokens限制范围内。
Now I want to share with you one more tip for how to use a large language model.
现在我想和你分享如何使用大
型语言模型的另一个技巧。
Calling the OpenAI API requires using an API key that's tied to either a free or a
调用OpenAI API需要使用与免费
或付费账户绑定的API密钥，
paid account and so many developers will write the API key in plain text like this into their
因此许多开发者会像这样将API密
钥以纯文本形式写入他们的
Jupyter notebook and this is a less secure way of using API keys that I would not recommend
Jupyter Notebook，这是一种使用API
密钥的不太安全的方式，我不建议
you use because it's just too easy to share this notebook with someone else or check this
你使用，因为这样太容易与他人共
享这个Notebook或将其检查到
into GitHub or something and thus end up leaking your API key to someone else.
GitHub或其他地方，从而泄露
你的API密钥给其他人。
In contrast what you saw me do in the Jupyter notebook was this piece of code where I use
相比之下，你在 Jupyter Notebook中
看到我做的是这段代码，我使用
a library dotenv and then run this command load dotenv find dotenv to read a local
一个库 dotenv，然后运行这个命令 load
dotenv find dotenv 来读取一个本地
file which is called dotenv that contains my secret key.
文件，叫做 .env，里面包含了我的密钥。
And so with this code snippet I have locally stored a file called dotenv that contains
所以通过这段代码片段，我在本地存储
了一个名为 .env 的文件，其中包含
my API key and this loads it into the operating systems environmental variable and then os.get
我的 API 密钥，然后将其加载到操作系
统的环境变量中，然后 os.getenv，
env, OpenAI API key stores it into this variable and in this whole process I don't ever have
OPENAI_API_KEY将其存储到这个变
量中，在整个过程中，我不需要将
to enter the API key in plain text in unencrypted plain text into my Jupyter notebook.
API 密钥以明文形式输入到我
的 Jupyter Notebook中。
this is a general method for storing different API keys from lots of different online services
这是一种用于存储来自许多不同在线
服务的不同 API 密钥的通用方法
that you might want to use and call from your Jupyter notebook.
你可能想要使用并从你的
Jupyter Notebook中调用。
The- I think the degree to which prompting is revolutionizing AI application development
我认为，提示（prompting）正在革新AI
应用开发的程度，仍然被低估了。
is still underappreciated.
In the traditional supervised machine learning workflow like the restaurant review sentiment
在传统的监督式机器学习工作流中，就像
我刚才提到的餐厅评论好评/差评分类
classification example that I touched on just now, if you want to build a classifier to
的例子，如果你想建立一个分类器来
classify restaurant review positive or negative sentiments you at first get a bunch of label
分类餐厅评论的正面或负面情感，
你首先需要获得一堆标签数据，
data maybe hundreds of examples this might take I don't know weeks maybe a month then
也许是几百个例子，这可能需
要几周，也许一个月。然后，
you would train a model on data and getting an appropriate open source model tuning on
你会在数据上训练一个模型，
获取一个合适的开源模型，
the model evaluating it that might take days weeks maybe even a few months and then you
对模型进行调优，评估模型，这可能需要几
天、几周甚至几个月的时间。接下来，
might have to find a cloud service to deploy it and then get your model uploaded to the
您可能需要找到一个云服务来部
署它，然后将模型上传到云端，
cloud and then run the model and finally be able to call your model and again not
然后运行模型，最后才能调用你的
模型。再说，这种情况并不少见，
uncommon for this to take a team a few months to get working.
这可能需要一个团队几个
月的时间才能完成。
In contrast with prompting based machine learning when you have a text application you can specify
与基于提示的机器学习相比，当你有
一个文本应用程序时，你可以指定
a prompt this can take minutes maybe hours if you need to iterate a few times to get
一个提示，这可能需要几分钟甚至几个
小时，如果你需要迭代几次才能得到
an effective prompt and then in hours maybe at most days but frankly more often hours
一个有效的提示，然后在几个小时甚至最
多几天内，但坦率地说，更多的是几个小时
you can have this running using API calls and start making calls to the model and once
你可以使用API调用来运行这个
程序，并开始调用模型，一旦
you've done that in just again maybe minutes or hours you can start calling the model and
你完成了这个过程，可能只需要几分钟或
几个小时，你就可以开始调用模型并
start making inferences and so there are applications that used to take me maybe six months or a
开始进行推断，所以有些应用程序过
去可能需要我花费六个月甚至一
year to build that you can now build in minutes or hours maybe very small numbers of days
年的时间来构建，现在你可以在几分
钟或几小时内，甚至很少的几天内
using prompting and this is revolutionizing what AI applications can be built quickly.
使用提示来构建，这正在彻底改变
可以快速构建的AI应用程序。
One important caveat this applies to many unstructured data applications including specifically
一个重要的注意事项是，这适用于许
多非结构化数据应用，包括特别是
text applications and maybe increasingly vision applications although the vision technology
文本应用程序，也许越来越多的
视觉应用程序，尽管视觉技术
is much less mature right now but it's kind of getting there.
目前还不够成熟，但它正
在朝这个方向发展。
This recipe doesn't really work for structured data applications meaning machine learning
这个方法对于结构化数据应用（
即机器学习）并不十分适用，
applications on tabular data with lots of numerical values in the Excel spreadsheet
在Excel表格中有大量数
值的表格数据应用上，
say but for applications to which this does apply the fact that AI components can be built
但对于适用的应用来说，AI组
件可以快速构建的事实，
so quickly is changing the workflow of how the entire system might be built.
正在改变整个系统可能构建的工作流程。
Building entire system might still take days or weeks or something but at least this piece
构建整个系统可能仍然需要几天
或几周的时间，但至少这部分
will show how to use these components to evaluate the input to a customer service assistant
如何使用这些组件来评估
客户服务助手的输入，
and this will be part of a bigger example that you see developed through this course
这将是一个更大示例的一部
分，您将在本课程中看到